Either the Culeda or the artists,
o la culerada o las artistas a ver
well, I woke up quite late, around
bueno pues he despertado bastante tarde
eleven, it must have been
a las once base
past 3000, and well, I had
me pasaran las 3000 y nada pues
lunch, I drank my decaf coffee
almorzado me tomo mi café descafeinado
due to my precarious state of health,
debido al precario estado de salud
I showered, shaved because I
me he duchado un afeitado porque yo
also shave, which is what you do, which would
también me afeito que lo que hacéis que
n't be more, but I'd look like
no sería más todavía pero parecería
Ademar or GPS,
el ademar o gps
so I also shaved, and why am I
entonces también me afeitado y porque os
telling you all this? It's with all this, whatever you don't want to talk about,
cuenta todo esto es con todo esto lo que
because I don't want to talk about
no quieras porque no quiere hablar de
football
fútbol
because every time you wake up and the first thing you
porque cada despiertas y lo primero que
think is, was it
piensas es
real? Yes, it didn't happen, it happened, it was
fue de verdad sí no
n't a nightmare, they
pasó sucedió no fue una pesadilla
scored 8-8 on us, like the 8 I have
nos metieron 88 como el 8 que tengo aquí
tattooed here on my leg,
tatuado en la pierna
8 with the 8 that Stoichkov wears, 8 with the one Andrés
8 con el 8 que lleva a stoichkov 8 con
Iniesta wore, the best midfielder I've ever
andrés iniesta el mejor centrocampista y
seen, 8 with the one Arthur wears,
yo visto en mi vida 8 con el que lleva
a scoundrel who I
gonorreas arthur un sinvergüenza que
hope they don't pay his salary beyond
espero que no le paguen el sueldo de más
whether they had to sell him or not, because he
allá de si lo tenían que vender o no que
was a player I liked a lot,
era un jugador que me gustaba mucho
football-wise, they behave like a  A
futbolísticamente se comportan como un
scoundrel, like most
sinvergüenza como la mayoría de
Brazilians, 0% professional. I hope his
brasileños 0 profesional espero que sus
teammates, if they have any
compañeros si tiene un poco de
pride, if they run into Bárcena,
de orgullos si se encuentran por bárcena
they punch him in the mouth because
le metan un puñetazo en la boca porque
he'd leave the ski team. I'm not a
dejaría al equipo de esquí no soy de muy
bad professional, beyond that, I insist,
mal profesional más allá de que insisto
I think he's a very good footballer. I don't know, I just don't know
me parece muy buen futbolista
what you think. I've seen
no sé es que no sé qué pensáis visto ya
a million memes, some quite
un millón de memes algunos bastante
good, like the one of him waving with 8 of 28
buenos como el de saludando con 8 de 28
fingers. It's very quick to react to people. I'd
dedos es muy rápida a la gente me
like to know how to make those kinds of montages.
gustaría saber hacer esos montajes
Some are quite bad, like
algunos bastante malos como bueno típico
the typical billiard ball one, and so on.
la bola de billar y tal
Many remember '72, I think it was a
muchos recordando el 72 creo que fue un
'72 Germany-Brazil match. I think it was
72 de alemania brasil yo creo que fue
worse because it was in a World Cup, and
peor porque fue en un mundial y siembra
so it would be a personal humiliation.
así lo sería humillación personal es que
The Germans are very brutal, they have no
los alemanes son muy brutos no tienen
hearts, they are very cruel.
corazones agentes son muy crueles
Anyone else would have left today in the 5.
cualquier otro habría deja hoy en el 5
I remember perfectly that he was on the
yo recuerdo perfectamente que está en el
field the day that
campo el día que
the great Barça that Guardiola was creating
el gran barça que se está gestando de
connected with Enrique when he was
guardiola conectó con enrique con
a month old and was a bullet, with
con un mes y que era una bala con
Iniesta, with Xavi, from 24 to Bayern,
iniesta con xavi de 24 al bayern
I think.  For 40 minutes like that, Bayern,
yo creo que 40 minutos así el bayern
I remember Demichelis was there, poor guy,
recuerdo que está demichelis ahí pobre
22-4, but we could have put 12 past them.
22 4 pero les podemos haber metido 12 y
Well, Guardiola's Barça wasn't like that, to be
bueno pues el barça de guardiola no no
honest. They don't brutally dominate the
no era así la verdad no te domina el
game, but they don't see you coming. In
partido brutalmente pero no te ven día 8
fact, sometimes
de hecho a veces
after dominating, they're much
después de dominar el estar mucho más
tighter than they were yesterday, they
ajustado de lo que el dominio ayer te
attack, attack, attack. Both full-
ataca te ataca te ataca suben los dos
backs go up from the center, one full-back, the
laterales del centro un lateral el slate
left winger, takes on your whole team, and the
izquierdo se mea todo tu equipo y el
right winger comes in and
lateral derecho entra la pequeña y te
finishes you off,
remata el board
a savage, unworked attack. Well, that's how they
una salvajada que no es trabajada
put 8 past us, and it's very hard,
pues eso nos metieron 8 y es muy duro
very hard to take in. And sadder today
muy duro de asimilar y más triste hoy
than yesterday, in a way, because
que ayer una parte que ayer porque
I
pensaba
envisioned a different scenario. I know
visualice otro escenario ya sé que
Busquets isn't the Busquets he used to be, but
busquets no es el busquets que era pero
I thought that, well, we could have a
pensar que bueno pues podías hacer un
good game when we were all together. When
buen partido cuando todos juntos cuando
I saw that four midfielders started,
vi que salían cuatro centrocampistas
well, it wasn't my favorite on any of my four
bueno no era mi favorito en mis cuatro
fronts on the pitch, but
frentes dentro pista favorito pero
I thought that would help us stay together. I also didn't
pensaba que eso ayudaría a estar juntos
expect Bayern to
que tampoco esperaba que el bayern
push their defense back into midfield like you
sacara la defensa en el mediocampo como
would against a team  Very, very, very
harías ante un equipo muy muy muy
small, lacking resources. Well, it
pequeño que no tiene recursos
was a brilliant move that we
bueno pues fue acertadísimo que en los
scored a goal in the first 10 minutes. Maybe we
10 minutos metimos un gol puede o se
scored 3, and that was it for Barça. After 10 minutes, what are
metió 3 ahí se acabó el barça a los 10
we going to do
minutos que vamos a hacer
beyond the game? I don't know, it's not what I'm used to.
más allá del partido que no sé no es lo
My roots, yesterday was Space Jam. I'm like
que yo mis raíces que ayer fue space jam
the movie Space Jam where
soy la peli space jam que unos
aliens steal
alienígenas le roban los superpoderes a
the NBA players' superpowers.
los jugadores de la nba
Jordan to the rescue, Jordan
- a seguir jordan al rescate jordan que
teaming up with Bugs Bunny and a bunch of
se junta con bugs bunny con una serie de
players no one wanted to be. A bit like
jugadores que nadie quería ser un poco
Space Jam, it'll be Jordan, but it's like in
space jam me será jordan pero como si en
Space Jam Jordan also had his
space jam a jordan también le han
superpowers taken away. Socially, it's the
quitado los superpoderes social a lo
same thing, they take away
mismo es le quitan los superpoderes a
everyone's superpowers. I think that suddenly makes them
todos creo que lo cual genera de repente
incredibly clumsy. What's
se vuelven ultra patosos lo que está
for you is Win, Son Bradley, who are the law. It was
para ti win son bradley que son la ley
for Toxo, there was no need to take them away. You can't. Well,
era para toxo no hacía falta que le
yesterday that's what it was. I
quitaran no se puede pues ayer precia
know I don't like that fear, but
eso ya sé que ese miedo no me gusta pero
yesterday it was ridiculous. The center backs could
es que ayer era ridículo los centrales
n't make a save, couldn't make a save. Keep going
no daban una salva no daba a una seguir
within a franchise, Jon looked like a
dentro de una franquicia jon parecía un
kid.  Busquets, who looked like a retired player, I mean, it's
niño busquets que parecía un jugador
very vast, you have Tegel, he started
o sea es muy vasta tenés tegel empezó a
missing passes, he started to doubt himself, he started to
fallar pases empezó a dudar empezó a
make runs, rallies, everything, I do
hacer salidas rallies queda todo
n't know, Space Jam, but like crazy, no, no, no, no,
no sé space jam pero a lo bestia no no
my imaginary problem, he
no no mi imaginario problema de se
imagined they were going to score 8 against us, I don't
imaginaba que nos iban a meter 8
know, vacation starts today, by the way, a disaster, a disaster, I'll try to make the most of it, I'll try to think about other things besides football. All this, Piqué came out saying that there were no structural problems at the club, that there should be elections, we don't all know why there won't be elections,
sabemos todos porque no habrá elecciones
and we don't all know because they have to
y no lo sabemos todos porque tienen que
cover up everything that
tapar todo lo que han robado
all those Brazilians have stolen, I insist, all
todos los brasileños esos insisto todos
the shady dealings, your own net, not even by
los chanchullos ar tu propia ni neto por
civilians,
civiles
after all, a player never sold
tras estas un todo jugar jamás vendido
like, for example, Barça, every European, I read
como por ejemplo culé ya cada europea
that Chelsea offered 30 million
ley que el chelsea ofrecía 30 millones
from zero, I never imagined that this player would
de cero yo nunca imagina que éste
reach that market value,
jugaría llegar a ese valor de mercado
but well, he's transformed, like an Indian,
pero bueno de transformase mal de indio
wanting to sell everything like someone who
como quiere más vender a todo como quien
sells anyone, that we're short,
vende a cualquiera que nos dentro duros
sell it and out, I don't
venderlo y fuera
know if the one here, who obviously has the
no sé si la aquí que tiene obviamente la
figure of Quique Setién, remains  He's been completely undermined,
figura de quique setién queda tocadísimo
everything he preached
o sea todo lo que todo lo que pregonaba
has been exposed as him being a
ha quedado ha quedado como un entrenador
very cowardly coach. I truly believe he's
muy cobarde que yo creo de verdad lo
genuinely afraid that they're
creo que te dé miedo real de que esto me
going to attack me, just like Louis usually does.
van a pegar es como louis suele a pegar
If I change him, not just because of yesterday's changes,
si lo cambio no no por cambiar de ayer
if we have to say who can no
si tenemos que decir quién ya no puede
longer play for Barça, starting with Luis
jugar más el barça empezado por luis
Suárez,
suárez
and then there would be a list of five or
y luego habría canción activa de cinco o
six players. If Busquets is the one who has to accept
seis si busquets quien sería que asumir
that he won't be a starter in most
que no va a ser titular en la mayoría de
matches, that midfielder has to
los partidos en el partido es importante
go. I don't care
ese medio se tiene que ir se me da igual
who comes in, he'll have to endure it. We have to keep him at
quien venga aguanta tengamos que tener a
right-back for 698 years, while he's
698 años mal de lateral derecho mientras
not a good midfielder. He's passable,
no vea de centrocampista
but I don't know, he has to go. What happened
pasable pero no sé no se tiene que ir es
yesterday is
que lo de ayer es
absolutely incomprehensible. And with
es absolutamente incomprensible y con
those who stay, building and knowing
los que se quede construyendo y sabiendo
that this is going to be a long road, a very, very
que esto va a ser un camino largo camino
long road, because you haven't gotten
muy muy largo porque no lo has acertado
anything right in recent years, in matters
nada de los últimos años en asuntos
unrelated to certain rumors, squandering
ajenos a cierta habladas dilapidado el
money. I don't know, I don't know
dinero
if they'll want
no sé no sé si querrán que vuelva a
Coutinho back to see us.  In 15 minutes, an
coutinho a vernos en 15 minutos
assist and 2 goals, you know, not the
asistencia y 2 goles ya se sabe no la la
ex-boyfriend's curse, but less
ley del ex pero menos
so from my side, more affected
asia de parte de mi más afectado a
than some players. Thiago
thiago que algunos jugadores a thiago
Alcántara was tempted, I mean, I
alcántara estaba estaba tentado o sea lo
saw him, it hurt him, where he was going to be,
veía si estaba le dolía de donde haber
another of the great historical halls
otro de los grandes salones históricos
at Barça, that
en el barça
price. Quite a few messages from
que ese precio bastante mensajes de
many people from many places in the world.
mucha gente de muchos sitios del mundo
Curiously, I haven't received any
curiosamente no he recibido ningún
messages from Madrid fans laughing, and I have a
mensaje de madridistas riéndose y tengo
lot of Madrid friends, and lately,
un montón de amigos del madrid y tarde
I think it's been so hard that I didn't even
yo creo que ha sido tan duro que no
want to laugh. Also, whenever
quería ni reirse también siempre cuando
they ask, I'm not going to laugh either. I
ellos piden yo tampoco voy a reír me lo
enjoy it when Madrid loses,
lo gozo cuando el madrid pierde como
but not by
pero no no
sending, right? They've
enviando verdad
lost,
hay perdido
sorry again, so that
perdón de nuevo para es para que se
800 trillion memes can be made. I'll
hagan 800 trillones de memes meme
tell you that I'm here for stories. To
le diré que estoy acá para historias a
this 28, forever, it
este 28 para siempre
always hurts me that with what happened in Rome,
siempre me duele que con lo de roma
Liverpool, and
liverpool y
yesterday, it
y lo de ayer
can turn into
se puede volver
victimhood, into a defeatism that was what
victimismo a un derrotismo que era lo
this team had before Johan Cruyff,
que a este equipo antes de johan cruyff
before he arrived, before his project.
antes de llegar proyecto del mismo
But  There are people who say Núñez was a
pero hay gente que dice núñez fue una
president,
presidenta
all that devastation that disaster caused, we
todo lo que ha devastado ese desastre le
give her a few slaps like, what kind of Madrid did
damos unos pupas como qué tipo de madrid
we have in 10 days?
teníamos 10 días
All that was reversed, first by finishing it
todo eso se revirtió primero concluirlo
with Guardiola, all that has been the
con con guardiola todo lo que ha sido la
Messi era, and I'm afraid that we'll go back to
era messi y me da miedo de que de que se
that, I'm afraid that
vuelva a volver a eso me da miedo de que
now a team has been built that won't measure up at all, what will they
ahora se construyó un equipo que no dé
understand? And kids,
que entenderán y chavales
well, like when they kick
trinca bueno pues como cuando se echa
Quaresma and Simao out, yes, good
cuaresma a quaresma y simao si buenos
players, but well, at 20 years old, a
jugadores pero bien con 20 años un
team that's a disaster, what are they going to
equipo que es un desastre que van a
do? Well, nothing, by the way, Quaresma was chosen
hacer pues nada que por cierto se eligió
instead of Cristiano Ronaldo
a quaresma en lugar de cristiano ronaldo
[Music] what,
[Música]
really, some people... well,
que ojo de verdad algunos bueno
to conclude, a hug, another hug,
para concluir un abrazo otro abrazo ya
calling a hug and a hug to all those
llamando un abrazo y abrazo a toda esa
Barça people who are suffering, trying to
gente del barça que sufre intentan
enjoy other things, trying, I didn't
disfrutar de otras cosas intentar no se
think I was going to throw myself into
pensaba yo que me voy a volcar otra vez
the NBA again,
en la nba
which by the way, is back this year, the NBA
que por cierto está esta vuelta la nba
Ultimate NBA.com, ultimatenba.com is the
ultimate nba.com ultimate nba.com es la
website that was created a  A million years old, it's still
web que crea hace un millón de años
active in its car thanks
todavía sigue activa en su auto gracias
to Demián, and well, if you want, if you want to
a a demián y bueno si queréis si queréis
say, "I'm going to change the axis to stop playing football
decir paso de eje para pasar de fútbol
for a while because of my age," well, you don't have
por un tiempo por la edad pues bueno no
those disappointments, even if they're from a
te has esos disgustos aunque sean de un
team, you have those disappointments, well, a
equipo lo tienes esos disgustos pues un
good entertainment
buen entretenimiento
that the web in 2001 when, when the Barça
que la web en 2001 cuando cuando el bar
Zela was such a disaster that it was impossible,
zela tamaño desastre que era imposible
impossible to watch,
imposible verlo
but you don't have to go back to your old ways,
pero no te hay que volver a las andadas
but well, as I
pero bueno
said, a hug to everyone, a kiss, it
lo dicho un abrazo a todos un beso
whipped us in a CO2 crash, it has been
fustigó en un choque de co2
worth it, we introduce ourselves through
da nosa le ha valido nos presentamos por
the hobbit of a marmoset, but well, what are we
el hobbit de un tití pero bueno qué le
going to do,
vamos a hacer
subscribe, if you like the channel, give it a like,
suscribiros se gusta el canal dale like
if I'm a very bad YouTuber, I never, never
si es que soy muy mal youtuber nunca
remember the belt of that because the
nunca acuerdo de cinto de eso porque la
bell is a man, to consume himself when he
campanilla es hombre consumirse cuando
uploads a video, when I upload a video
sube un vídeo cuando subo un vídeo
saying today we were pleased, Bayern, well,
diciendo hoy quedamos agradado bayern
no, because I want to be able to and nothing,
pues que no porque quiero poder y nada
force Barça and we'll win again
fuerza barça y ya volvemos a ganar
[Music]
[Música]